district158.org 2009-12-21

# Online Privacy Statement

Online Privacy Statement
The School District respects the privacy of all Web site visitors to the extent permitted by law. This
Online Privacy Statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this Web site collects
information, the uses to which that information will be put, and the ways in which we will protect any
information you choose to provide us.
There are four types of information that this site may collect during your visit: network traffic logs,
Web-visit logs, cookies, and information voluntarily provided by you.
 Network Traffic Logs
In the course of ensuring network security and consistent service for all users, the District employs
software programs to do such things as monitor network traffic, identify unauthorized access or access
to nonpublic information, detect computer viruses and other software that might damage District
computers or the network, and monitor and tune the performance of the District network. In the
course of such monitoring, these programs may detect such information as e-mail headers, addresses
from network packets, and other information. Information from these activities is used only for the
purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the District's networks and computer systems.
Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties without your
consent unless required by law.
 Web - Visit Logs
District Web sites may collect and store information from online visitors to help manage those sites
and improve service. This information includes the pages visited on the site, the date and time of the
visit, the Internet address (URL or IP address) of the referring site, the domain name and IP address
from which the access occurred, the version of browser used, the capabilities of the browser, and
search terms used on our search engines. This site makes no attempt to identify individual visitors
from this information; any personally identifiable information is not released to external parties
without your consent unless required by law.
Cookies
Cookies are pieces of information stored by your Web browser on behalf of a Web site and returned to
the Web site on request. This site may use cookies for two purposes: to carry data about your
current session at the site from one Web page to the next, and to identify you to the site between
visits. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you may turn them off in your browser, or may set your
browser to ask you before accepting a new cookie. Some pages may not function properly if the
cookies are turned off. Unless otherwise notified on the site, we will not store data, other than for
these two purposes, in cookies. Cookies will remain on your computer, and accordingly we neither
store cookies on our computers nor forward them to any external parties. We do not use cookies to
track your movement among different Web sites and do not exchange cookies with other entities.
Information Voluntarily Provided by You
In the course of using this Web site, you may choose to provide us with information to help us serve
your needs. For example, you may send us electronic mail (through a mailer or a Web form) to
request information, you may sign up for a mailing list, or you may send us your address so we may
send you an application to other material. Any personally identifiable information you send us will be
used only for the purpose indicated. Requests for information will be directed to the appropriate staff
to respond to the request, and may be recorded to help us update our site to better respond to similar
requests. We will not sell, exchange, or otherwise distribute your personally identifiable information
without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer
than necessary for normal operations. Each Web page requesting information discloses the purpose of

that information. If you do not wish to have the information used in that manner, you are not required
to provide it.
Please contact the person listed on the specific page, or listed below, with questions or concerns on
the use of personally identifiable information.
 Web Links to Non-District Sites
District Web sites provide links to other World Wide Web sites or resources. We do not control these
sites and resources, do not endorse them, and are not responsible for their availability, content, or
delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by this Online Privacy Statement; they
may have their own policies or none at all. Often you can tell you are leaving a District Web site by
noting the URL of the destination site.
Questions or concerns: e-mail, helpdesk@district158.org
Contact Us
